Gregory Peck stars as the man who led thousands in a daring escape
to freedom - right under the nose of the Gestapo.
The Scarlet and the Black is a drama, history, tv
movie film directed by Jerry London.
Hugh O'Flaherty is a Vatican official in 1943-45 who has been hiding downed
pilots, escaped prisoners of war, and Italian resistance families.
His activities become so large that the Nazis decide to
assassinate him the next time he leaves the Vatican.
Monsignor Hugh O'Flaherty, played by Gregory Peck.
Col. Herbert Kappler, played by Christopher Plummer.
Pope Pius XII, played by John Gielgud.
Father Vittorio, played by Raf Vallone.
Capt. Hirsch, played by Kenneth Colley.
Gen. Max Helm, played by Walter Gotell.
The Scarlet and the Black is a 1983 Italian-American international co-production made-for-television
historical war drama film directed by Jerry London, and starring Gregory Peck and Christopher Plummer.
Based on J.
Gallagher's book The Scarlet Pimpernel of the Vatican (published in 1967), the film tells the story of Monsignor Hugh
O'Flaherty, a real-life Irish Catholic priest who saved thousands of Jews and escaped Allied POWs in Rome.
CBS distributed more than 500,000 scripts of The Scarlet and the Black to students in elementary and high schools
throughout the country, to be read aloud in class to stimulate student interest in English and history.
The title The Scarlet and the Black is a reference not only to the black cassock and scarlet sash worn by
monsignors and bishops in the Catholic Church, but also to the dominant colors of Nazi Party regalia.
The tone is emotional.